<?xml version="1.0"?><metadata><idinfo><citation><citeinfo><origin>Minnesota Pollution Control Agency</origin><title>Assessed Waters, Minnesota, 2020</title><pubinfo><publish>Minnesota Pollution Control Agency</publish></pubinfo><pubdate>20211115</pubdate><onlink>https://gisdata.mn.gov/dataset/env-assessed-proposed-water-2018</onlink></citeinfo></citation><descript><abstract>This is a set of the waterbodies assessed by MPCA's surface water quality assessment process for the 2020 303(d)/305(b) integrated report to EPA. 

Please consult the metadata of the individual datasets for details on their lineage.</abstract><purpose>These data are intended to be used for planning, informational, and cartographic purposes related to surface water quality in Minnesota.</purpose><supplinf>State of Minnesota</supplinf></descript><timeperd><current>These data reflect the state of the MPCA's surface water assessment database as of the dataset publication date.</current><timeinfo><sngdate><caldate>20211115</caldate></sngdate></timeinfo></timeperd><status><progress>Complete</progress><update>None Planned</update></status><spdom><bounding><westbc>-97.23</westbc><eastbc>-89.53</eastbc><northbc>49.37</northbc><southbc>43.5</southbc></bounding></spdom><keywords><place><placekey>Minnesota</placekey></place><theme><themekt>ISO 19115</themekt><themekey>inlandWaters, surface water, water chemistry, water quality, assessment, assessed</themekey></theme></keywords><accconst>None</accconst><useconst>None</useconst><ptcontac><cntinfo><cntperp><cntorg>Minnesota Pollution Control Agency</cntorg><cntper>Kristofor Parson</cntper></cntperp><cntpos>Data Specialist</cntpos><cntaddr><addrtype>Mailing and Physical</addrtype><address>525 S. Lake Ave.</address><city>Duluth</city><state>MN</state><postal>55802</postal></cntaddr><cntvoice>218-302-6622</cntvoice><cntemail>kristofor.parson@state.mn.us</cntemail></cntinfo></ptcontac></idinfo><dataqual><logic>These data have been audited to ensure every waterbody included in the 305(b) submission to EPA has a corresponding feature in this dataset, and that the use judgments are consistent between this spatial dataset and the assessment database as of the publication date. There are three lakes included in the impaired waters list ( 69-0254-01, 69-0254-02, and 69-0254-04 ) which are included in this dataset as a single waterbody (69-0254-00). Date of test:11/15/21</logic><complete>These data contain a feature for every waterbody in the 305(b) inventory of assessed waters. High-resolution NHD is the primary dataset from which these features are drawn. If no feature exists in the NHD, MPCA staff will digitize a feature.</complete><posacc><horizpa><horizpar>Statements of horizontal positional accuracy are based on accuracy statements made for U.S. Geological Survey topographic quadrangle maps. These maps were compiled to meet National Map Accuracy Standards. For horizontal accuracy, this standard is met if at least 90 percent of points tested are within 0.02 inch (at map scale) of the true position. Additional offsets to positions may have been introduced where feature density is high to improve the legibility of map symbols. In addition, the digitizing of maps is estimated to contain a horizontal positional error of less than or equal to 0.003 inch standard error (at map scale) in the two component directions relative to the source maps. Visual comparison between the map graphic (including digital scans of the graphic) and plots or digital displays of points, lines, and areas, is used as control to assess the positional accuracy of digital data. Digital map elements along the adjoining edges of data sets are aligned if they are within a 0.02 inch tolerance (at map scale). Features with like dimensionality (for example, features that all are delineated with lines), with or without like characteristics, that are within the tolerance are aligned by moving the features equally to a common point. Features outside the tolerance are not moved; instead, a feature of type connector is added to join the features.
This statement is generally true for the most common sources of NHD data. Other sources and methods may have been used to create or update NHD data. In some cases, additional information may be available from the data provider upon request.</horizpar></horizpa></posacc><attracc><attraccr>These data represent the current state of the MPCA's Assessment Database (ADB) as of the publication date. Every effort is made to ensure that attributes of waterbodies in the ADB are correct.</attraccr></attracc></dataqual><distinfo><resdesc>Assessed Waters, Minnesota, 2020</resdesc><distliab>	NOTICE: The Geographic Information System (GIS) Data to which this notice is attached are made available pursuant to the Minnesota Government Data Practices Act (Minnesota Statutes Chapter 13). THE GIS DATA ARE PROVIDED TO YOU AS IS AND WITHOUT ANY WARRANTY AS TO THEIR PERFORMANCE, MERCHANTABILITY, OR FITNESS FOR ANY PARTICULAR PURPOSE. The GIS Data were developed by the Minnesota Pollution Control Agnecy for its own internal business purposes. The Minnesota Pollution Control Agency does not represent or warrant that the GIS Data or the data documentation are error-free, complete, current, or accurate. You are responsible for any consequences resulting from your use of the GIS Data or your reliance on the GIS Data. You should consult the data documentation for this particular GIS Data to determine the limitations of the GIS Data and the precision with which the GIS Data may depict distance, direction, location, or other geographic features. If you transmit or provide the GIS Data (or any portion of it) to another user, the GIS Data must include a copy of this disclaimer.</distliab><stdorder><ordering>These data may be requested from Kristofor Parson, MNIT @  Minnesota Pollution Control Agency.</ordering></stdorder><distrib><cntinfo><cntperp><cntorg>Minnesota Pollution Control Agency</cntorg><cntper>Kristofor Parson</cntper></cntperp><cntpos>Data Specialist</cntpos><cntaddr><addrtype>mailing and physical</addrtype><address>525 S. Lake Ave.</address><city>Duluth</city><state>MN</state><postal>55802</postal></cntaddr><cntvoice>218-302-6622</cntvoice><cntemail>kristofor.parson@state.mn.us</cntemail></cntinfo></distrib></distinfo><metainfo><metd>20211115</metd><metstdn>Minnesota Geographic Metadata Guidelines</metstdn><metstdv>1.2</metstdv><metextns><onlink>http://www.mngeo.state.mn.us/committee/standards/mgmg/metadata.htm</onlink></metextns><metc><cntinfo><cntperp><cntorg>Minnesota Pollution Control Agency</cntorg><cntper>Kristofor Parson</cntper></cntperp><cntpos>Data Specialist</cntpos><cntaddr><addrtype>mailing and physical</addrtype><address>525 S. Lake Ave.</address><city>Duluth</city><state>MN</state><postal>55802</postal></cntaddr><cntvoice>218-302-6622</cntvoice><cntemail>kristofor.parson@state.mn.us</cntemail></cntinfo></metc></metainfo><spref><horizsys><planar><gridsys><gridsysn>Universal Transverse Mercator</gridsysn><utm><utmzone>15E</utmzone></utm></gridsys><planci><plandu>meters</plandu></planci></planar><geodetic><horizdn>NAD83</horizdn><ellips>GRS80</ellips></geodetic></horizsys></spref></metadata>